

Hamza Sadaqat

Nationality: Pakistani Date of birth: 10/12/1998 Gender: Male

C Phone number: (+92) 3415938652 Email address: hamzasdt786@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/Hamza-Sadaqat

O Home: Sadiqabad, Rawalpindi, (46200), (Pakistan)

ABOUT ME

Responsible and highly motivated professional with solid and diverse experience as a GIS Analyst, proficient in spatial and non-spatial data management, multiple GIS softwares, managing overall operations and optimizing organizational processes. Highly motivated, dependable, and demonstrates professionalism in handling various organizational functions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

GIS Manager

Changaiz Enterprises [07/2022 - Current]

City: Rawalpindi **Country:** Pakistan

- Worked closely with end users to identify GIS requirements, technical issues.
- Analyzed current business processes and recommends best practice solutions.
- · Perform research to find and expand existing data sets of cadastral records and administrative records.
- Maintained GIS' system by maintaining the GIS server which typically involves working with IT administrators to install and upgrade the necessary GIS software.
- Spatial and non-spatial data handling for around 20000 acres project area.
- · Contact external stakeholders for the field service, satellite and aerial photographs, and maps.
- Project management, and validation of GIS data according to company's SOPs.
- Present information to customers and stakeholders in oral or written format.

Assistant GIS Manager

Bahria Town Pvt. Limited [12/2021 - 06/2022]

City: Islamabad **Country:** Pakistan

I got promotion in my rank to Assistant GIS manager due to recognition of my hard work. There I performed:

- Researched legal descriptions and survey maps to verify property boundaries & areas and gather requisite information for mapping.
- Created GIS maps as requested by using ArcMap and relevant datasets.
- Assisted in data management and organization, including vector and raster data.
- Ensuring that all maps adhere to cartographic rules (scale, line size, color etc) before getting into production (hard copies).

GIS Assistant

Bahria Town Pvt. Limited [07/2021 - 11/2021]

City: Islamabad **Country:** Pakistan

- Developed a wide variety of computerized maps by interpreting source data, electronically digitizing the information into the computer database.
- Geo-referenced and Mosaicked land record called Musavi sheets and different types of maps and images.
- Produced georeferenced historical imagery and maps, and digitized new features as requested.
- Performed basic GIS operations under the direction of head GIS analyst, including using geoprocessing tools, and creating as well as editing geographic data sets.

Freelance Project Manager

Translate7 [01/2020 – 10/2021]

City: London

Country: United Kingdom

- I worked remotely and managed 50+ legal and general translation and transcription projects.
- Had worked with linguists of 20+ languages from different countries.

Medical transcriptionist

Eye Technologies Pvt. Ltd | US Based Company [01/2017 - 11/2020]

City: Rawalpindi **Country:** Pakistan

- Worked as Medical Transcriptionist and Transcription Specialist.
- Transcribe medical dictation 15 physicians from a home-based office.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Geo-informatics

[10/2018 - 06/2022]

University: PMAS Arid Agriculture University, Rawalpindi

CGPA: 3.81/4

GIS Surveyor

[01/2019 - 03/2019]

PSDF (Punjab Skills Development Fund)

Short Course | 360 hours

Grade: A+

Higher Secondary School Certificate (HSSC)

[08/2015 - 06/2017]

College: Punjab College of Information Technology

Grade: A

COURSES

Online Courses

Coursera Certified Courses:

Al for Everyone | DeepLearning.Al

Geospatial and Environmental Analysis | University of California Davis

Imagery, Automation and Applications | University of California Davis

Geodesign: Change Your World | The Pennsylvania State University

Sustainable Regional Principles, Planning and Transportation | Johns Hopkins University

Urbanization and Health | University of Copenhagen, University of Coimbra, Politecnia de Madrid

Sustainable Development Goals | Erasmus University Rotterdam

International Travel Preparation, Safety & Dohns Hopkins University

International and Cross-Cultural Negotiation | ESSEC Business School

Project Management | Google

Geo University Certified Courses:

Introduction to Cloudeo's geospatial solutions

Remote Sensing and Satellite Image Processing with the EOS Platform

Digital Image Processing using Python

ESRI Certified Courses:

Going Places with Spatial Analysis Python for Everyone

Getting Started with ArcGIS Pro

Udemy Certified Courses:

Application of Remote Sensing Techniques

Advanced Google Earth Engine (GEE) For Spatial Data Analysis

DataCamp Certified Course: Introduction to Python

Computer Course: Computer Fundamentals | Namo-e-Sahar Institute of Computer Technology

Certificates Link: https://github.com/Hamza-Sadaqat/Certificates

Technical Skills

Key Software: ArcGIS, ERDAS IMAGINE, QGIS, ENVI, eCognition Developer, GRASS GIS, ArcGIS CityEngine, ArcGIS Pro

Programming Environment: Python, GDAL, OGR, ArcPy, Google Earth Engine **General Software:** Minitab, MS Excel, MS Word, MS PowerPoint, Mendeley

Certification

Microsoft Technology Associate

Introduction to programming using python

PROJECTS

This section presents several practical academic projects undertaken during my undergraduate studies

Site suitability analysis for housing society | Nov 2018

Flood damage assessment and site suitability analysis for water reservoir dam | Mar 2019

Assessment of Urban Sprawl | December 2019

Shortest route and network analysis for emergency response | May 2020

Remote sensing assessment and spatio-temporal assessment of ecological carrying capacity | Jan 2021

Spatio-temporal analysis of crop assessment and yield estimation | Nov 2021

Geospatial analysis of wind induced soil loss | Feb 2022

Integration of satellite imagery for LULC and crop type mapping of agroeconomic zones of Punjab [Final year project] | Bachelor's Thesis Jul 2022

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Urdu

Other language(s):

English Hindko

LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING C1 LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2 SPOKEN PRODUCTION C2 SPOKEN INTERACTION C2

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Hobbies

Cartography | Photography | Cricket | Music | Traveling

VOLUNTEER WORK

Social and Volunteer Services

General Secretary SOGIRS

- Served as General Secretary of SOGIRS (Society of Geo-informatics & Remote Sensing) | 2019
- · Organized Annual GIS Day 2021 Celebrations and GIS Workshops
- · Organized GIS awareness Campaign at the occasion of University's Silver Jubilee celebration
- \cdot Voluntarily teach GIS practical i.e use of geoprocessing tools, model building in ArcMap, creating geodatabases, to new students.